<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Castell</string>

    <string name="home">Home</string>
    <string name="village">Village</string>
    <string name="wine">Wine</string>
    <string name="hospitality">Hospitality</string>
    <string name="folklore">Folklore</string>
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="welcome_message">Welcome to Castell!</string>
    <string name="general_info">The village of Castell lies near the romnatic forest range of the
        Steigerwald in Unterfanken (lower Franconion), Germany. It is also the seat of the noble
        dynasty of "Castell".
        \n
        \nThe village has a long standing tradition of viticulture. Some of Franconians finest wines
        are pressed in the Dom&#228;nenamt of Castell, the vineyard estate owned by the noble
        dynasty of Castell.
        \n
        \nCastell delights its visitors with beautiful landscapes, traditional Franconian dishes and
        of course the extraordinary wine, and enthralls friends of culture and history with
        historical sides and a wide array of concerts and other cultural events.</string>
    <string name="new_castle_name">The Castle of Castell</string>
    <string name="new_castle_info">The \"new\" castle of Castell is the current seat of the noble
        dynasty of Castell-Castell. The building works started in 1687 and were finished in 1691. It is a
        three winged structure in the style of the early baroque.</string>
    <string name="town_hall_name">Town Hall</string>
    <string name="town_hall_info">The Town Hall of Castell was built in 1848. Originally, it was the
        local school building. In the upper stocks, lessons were held up till 1969. Since 1978 it
        serves not only for as the town hall for Castell, but also for the incorporated communes
        Greuth and W&#252;stenfelden. The backside of the building is home of a home museum.</string>
    <string name="castell_bank_name">Castell Bank</string>
    <string name="castell_bank_info">The \"Comital Castell-Remlingen\'sche Country Credit-Casa\" of
        Castell was founded by Friedrich Adolph von Zwanziger in 1774. It was originally a welfare
        institution intended to help the impoverished farmers in the area with favourable credits
        as well as fighting the usury in the county.
        \n It was then transformed into the \"Princely Castell Bank\" during the 19th and 20th
        century. It is considered the oldes Bavarian bank and one of the few banks in private
        ownership, belonging to the dynasty of Castell.</string>
    <string name="church_name">Church St. Johannes</string>
    <string name="church_info">The evangelic-lutheran church St. Johannes is one of the oldest
        churches in the area. It was first mentioned in the 13th century. The current building was
        completed in 1792. The outside structure is held in the style of the late baroque, while
        the inner building is dominated by the classicism. </string>
    <string name="archive_name">The Archive</string>
    <string name="archive_info">The "Princely Archive of Castell" stores over 8000 documents from
        about the villages of the county Castell from 1224 to the 20th century.</string>
    <string name="castle_tower_name">The old Castle Tower</string>
    <string name="castle_tower_info">The old Castle Tower is the last standing remnant of the old
        fortress and castle of the counts of Castell-Castell. They where not build within village, but on
        two hills rising over the settlement: the Herrenberg (lords\' hill) and the Schloßberg
        (castle\'s hill).</string>
    <string name="casteller_wine_name">Casteller Wein</string>
    <string name="casteller_wine_info">Castell is a famous for its fine wines. The grapes cultivated
        in the vineyards around the village are mainly the typical Franconian varieties like
        M&#252;ller-Thurgau, Bacchus, Riesling, Domani and of course Silvaner, the traditionally
        most important grape of the area. A documents from 1659 implies that the first Franconian
        Silvaner was planted in Castell. \n A lot, but not all of the wine, are filled in
        Bocksbeutel, a traditional Franconian form for wine bottles.</string>
    <string name="vineyard_name">Vineyards</string>
    <string name="vineyard_info">There are seven vineyard sites surrounding Castell: Schlossberg,
        Reitsteig, Kirchberg, Trautberg, Hohnart, Kugelspiel and Bausch. The soil consists mainly
        out of clay and gypsum-keuper.</string>
    <string name="weinbergstulpe_name">Weinbergstulpen</string>
    <string name="weinbergstulpe_info">The bright yellow Weinbergstulpe is a flower that can be
        found in the vineyards around Castell. It blooms in bright yellows. In the spring, the
        people of Castell hold a feast to celebrated it, called \"Weinbergstulpenfest\".</string>
    <string name="schwan_name">Zum Schwan</string>
    <string name="schwan_info">The inn \"Zum Schwan\" (to the swan) offers traditional Franconian
        cuisine, wine and rooms for guests.</string>
    <string name="weinstall_name">Weinstall</string>
    <string name="weinstall_info">The restaurant "Weinstall" has been build in the stables of the
        new castle. It offers finest Franconian cuisine as well as wine from Castell.</string>
    <string name="gruener_baum_name">Gr&#252;ner Baum</string>
    <string name="gruener_baum_info">The tavern "Gr&#252;ner Baum" offers only drinks and is a
        meeting place for locals.</string>
    <string name="kniebrecher_name">Kniebrecher</string>
    <string name="kniebrecher_info">The Kniebrecher is a café and bistro. It offers food and drinks
        and is a popular meeting place for the locals. Its nem, which means \"knee breaker\" comes
        from the steep incline at which start it lies.</string>
    <string name="kerm_name">Kerm</string>
    <string name="kerm_info">The \"Kerm\" is a traditional fair in Franconian held to celebrate the
        benediction of the local church. In Castell, the Kerm takes place in the autumn and lasts
        for several days. An important part of it is the so called \"Kirchweihrede\" during which
        the young men of the village tell short stories and perform plays about funny occurrences
        that happened to the people over the year.
    </string>
    <string name="may_tree_name">Erection of the May Tree</string>
    <string name="may_tree_info">At the 30th of April, the young men of Castell erect the May Tree.
        It is traditionally a tall, slender birch with red-white ribbons in its crown. When the tree
        has been erected, it has to be guarded as the young people from the surrounding villages
        will try to steal each others trees. If a tree is successfully stolen, the young people
        who couldn\'t defend their tree have to pay a ransom of beer.</string>
    <string name="spectaculum_name">Spectaculum of Castell</string>
    <string name="spectaculum_info">In 2016 Castell celebrated its 1200 anniversary. The pinnacle
        of the celebration was a Medieval Market including a knight\'s festival performed by the
        stunt crew \"Geyers Enkel\" of the Florian-Geyer-Spiele in Giebelstadt.</string>
    <string name="gruendleinsloch_name">The Gr&#252;ndleinsloch</string>
    <string name="gruendleinsloch_info">The Gr&#252;ndleinsloch is a well outside the village of
        Castell. Known for its mysterious blue water, it is the center of many local legends.
        \n
        \nOne of the most famous tells of three young women visiting the feasts in the castle,
        enticing the young men with their beauty and grace, but always leaving before midnight.
        \nWhen some of the young men set the clock of the church tower at the wrong time to trick
        them into staying longer, they flee in panic as they hear the bell ring midnight.
        \nThe young men follow them and watch them running down to the well and throwing themselves
        inside it. However, once the young men themselves reach the well, they see to their horror
        a swirl of blood rising to the surface. The three young maidens never returned.
    </string>
    <string name="blue_woman_name">The Blue Woman of Castell</string>
    <string name="blue_woman_info">The Blue Woman is a guardian spirit of the dynasty of
        Castell-Castell.
        \n
        \nOnce a countess of Castell herself, she told her husband who was going to
        war that should he suffer great misery and knew now other way, he should look towards his
        home in the west during sundown and say her name three times. As the count becomes a captive
        rotting away in a forgotten prison of the enemy, he finally can\'t bear being separated from
        his family anymore, he calls his wife\'s name during sundown and is freed by a magical blue
        light that opens his chains, makes his guardians fall asleep and guides him to a pegasus
        which carries him home.
        \nWhen he arrives at home, however, everyone is grieving. Entering the castle, he learns
        that last night at sundown his wife sat at the window, looking eastwards as she suddenly
        whispered \"I\'m coming\" and fell dead to the floor.
        \n
        \nLater, during the peasants war, the blue woman appeared again. In a dream she showed
        the son of the count in the besieged castle a secret passage through which he could flee
        with his siblings and his mother.
        \n
        \nSource: "Zwischerlichten" by Teophil Steinbrenner, Gerhard Wahler, Auguste Steinberger and
        Felix von Fokczynski.
    </string>
    <string name="entries">Entries</string>
</resources>
